Jaclene Sini, Full Stack Software Engineer

770-880-0312 | Brooklyn, New York | They/Them jaclenesini@gmail.com | in/jac-lene | github.com/jac-lene

SUMMARY

Human-focused programmer with a desire to produce compassionate, engaging, and empowering user experiences. With past careers in a variety of industries, they have a unique and creative approach to work, life, and communication. Software development has allowed Jaclene to apply their specialized knowledge in ways that beautifully blend their unique abilities and life experience, and they would love to join your team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL

Databases - Postgres SQL, MongoDB | Other - RESTful Routing, JSON api

Libraries and Frameworks - React (class based and hooks), Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

SockLab Customizer, Frontend / Backend | Full Stack Engineer

July 2022

Solo 3 Week Sprint

- SockLab is a design experience that allows the user to customize a sock knitting pattern using a visual laboratory inspired by the custom design experience of shoe brands like Nike and Vans.
- Designed and engineered over a 3 week period, SockLab is a fully responsive, full stack MERN website with full CRUD functionality and RESTful Django framework.
- Engineered with React frontend, Django backend, Postgres SQL and bespoke UI with CSS styling.

Align Astrological Dating, <u>Frontend</u> / <u>Backend</u> | Full Stack Engineer, Project Manager

May 2022

3 Person Team, 2 Week Sprint

- Align is a swipe-based dating website that utilizes the zodiac to determine match compatibility.
- Designed and engineered over <2 week period, Align is a fully responsive, full stack MERN website with full CRUD and RESTful routing.
- Uses React along with a Mongo database and 3rd party APIs, Javascript, HTML, and CSS styling.

GYST Habit Tracker, Github | Full Stack Developer

April 2022

Solo 2 Week Sprint

- Gyst presents your daily doings in a minimalist, gender neutral interface with an at-a-glance view of your habits.
- Full CRUD, RESTful mobile application utilizing MongoDB and user generated data.
- Engineered with EJS, HTML, CSS, Javascript and Mongoose.

Raccoons, Github | Front End Developer

March 2022

Solo 2 Week Sprint

- Raccoons follows the structure of gaming classic Battleship, set in a brand new environment.
- Utilizes complex javascript, responsive CSS styling, and HTML.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tech Editor and Grader

Remote

Brooklyn Tweed · Freelance Mar 2017 - Oct 2019

- Re-engineered deliverables to incorporate size inclusivity, diversity, and style standards for \$10M dollar company
- Created and implemented system standards and style sheets for uniform language across departments
- Quality assured product for mathematical accuracy, readability, and brand compliance

Jaclene Sini, Full Stack Software Engineer

770-880-0312 | Brooklyn, New York | They/Them jaclenesini@gmail.com | in/jac-lene | github.com/jac-lene

Props Production Assistant Netflix, NBC/Universal

New York, New York Jun 2018 - Nov 2018

- Managed 100-200 high value products and quality assured prop selection for cross department collaborators.
- Fabricated props, conducted research, and organized purchases from over 100 outside stakeholders.
- Interfaced with high level, Oscar winning celebrity clientele to discuss and finalize cross department decisions

Yarn Coordinator Vogue Knitting Magazine/Soho Publishing

New York, New York

June 2016 - May 2018

- Project managed a team of over 200 designers, facilitating the production of 150 250 deliverables per 3
 month magazine and book cycle.
- Rehabilitated and refreshed social media campaigns by curating specialized content, increasing engagement by 75% within the first 2 months.
- Improved live event sales by targeting a wider age range and a more diverse demographic, resulting in sales growth for 300-500 stakeholders and affiliates.
- Designed and fabricated knitwear featured on The Late Show with Stephen Colbert and showcased by actress
 Krysten Ritter, enhancing company visibility by engaging over 3.81M viewers.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Remote

Software Engineering Immersive

January 2022 - July 2022

 Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 24-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.

Savannah College of Art and Design Film and Television, BFA

Savannah, Georgia September 2008 - May 2012